All plans go smoothly.
計畫一切順利
That's good.
如此甚好
Bless our new homeland
給予吾等新的故鄉祝福
and grant our enemies the joy of death.
並賜予吾等敵人死亡之喜悅
This moment is now upon us.
這個時刻就在眼前了
Dedicate the victory to Junoid.
將勝利獻給由諾伊德
Damn.
可惡
I was too careless.
太大意了…
Puppetmaster.
操偶師…
That guy is…
那傢伙是…
Looks like everything's ready.
看來準備都己完成
Do you like it?
妳還喜歡嗎
This mask is new and specially made.
這個面具是特別訂製的新品
After all, this is our troupe's final performance.
畢竟這可是本團最後的表演
It's okay. Don't worry.
沒事 不用擔心
It's an improvisational performance now.
現在是即興演出
There are no written lines and all the actors play in their own way.
沒有既定台詞 所有的演員 都以各自的想法在演出這段戲劇…
No.
不…
This is not a play.
這並不是戲劇
Instead, it's the true nature presented by the actors themselves.
而是演員本身所呈現的真實姿態
Everyone here is an excellent actor.
所有的人都是出色演員
They will never bore the audience.
絕不會讓觀眾覺得無趣的
Alright, please enjoy
好了 請各位觀賞吧
this real-life improvisational performance
這齣由脫線人偶所編織出的
made by stray puppets.
真實即興劇
(Metallic Rouge)
《金屬口紅》
Rouge.
露瓊
Are you okay?
妳沒事啊
Gene.
吉恩
Thanks to you guys breaking in here, I could escape.
多虧有你們的攻擊 我才能趁亂逃出來
I always believe you would come.
我一直都相信妳一定會來的
Thank you, Rouge.
謝謝妳 露瓊
I'm truly moved.
心動…
I know where id is.
我知道伊德的位置在哪裡
What Alters did is wrong.
奧塔的做法是錯的
-We must rely on ourselves to build a new world -Hey, this is…
-我們要靠自己 -喂 這是…
-that does not discriminate against Neans. -Right.
-創作一個不會歧視涅安的新世界 -嗯 應該錯不了
We want to build…
我們要創作出來…
What are you doing, Rouge?
妳這是做什麼 露瓊
I didn't teach you that.
哥哥不記得有把妳教育成 會做出這種事的孩子
I've never been taught by you.
我才沒有被你教過
You underestimated us.
太小看人了吧
How can we fall for the same thing over and over again?
我們怎麼可能一再地上同樣的當
Boring.
真是無趣
Just play with me.
妳們就再陪我玩一下嘛
I have a lot of touching lines to say.
我還準備了 很多令人感動的台詞要說呢
Cut the crap. Where is Gene?
少囉嗦 吉恩在哪裡
I'll take you.
我帶妳們去
I'll take both of you to where he is.
帶兩位去吉恩・容格哈特的所在之處
What do you want?
你什麼意思
I just want to enjoy this a bit more.
我只是想再多享受一下罷了
You understand the character of our Queen, don't you?
兩位也懂我們的女王陛下的為人吧
Oh!
啊…
She is stubborn and seldom smiles.
為人頑固 面無表情
And you are like the embodiment of humor, a combination of funny and witty ones.
就這點來說 妳們則是幽默化身 滑稽與詼諧的集合體
Is he complimenting us?
他是在稱讚我們嗎
Not at all!
才不是咧
You don't get to talk about us.
就你沒資格說我們啦
Life is all about choices.
人生就是不斷的選擇
Believe it or not, it's your freedom.
信不信都是兩位的自由
Seven of Hearts.
紅心7
It means to open up the future.
開拓未來…
If it's the two of you,
如果是妳們兩位的話
I'm sure you can make this boring long play funny.
肯定能為這場又臭又長的戲 妝點出有趣又大膽的橋段
All right, please follow me.
好了 請隨我來
Someone is in battle.
有人正在戰鬥
Eden.
伊甸…
Hey, can we stop fighting?
我說啊 可以別打了嗎
Let's call this a draw, shall we?
這次就算我們平手好不好
I would never turn a blind eye
妨礙希爾維雅之人…
to anyone who stand in Silvia's way.
我絕不可能視而不見
Are you going to fight anyway?
無論如何都要打嗎
I will never let go of those
讓希爾維雅傷心之人
who upset Silvia.
我絕不可能放過
Just feel the pain.
用心體會痛楚吧
My friend,
吾友
take this move of mine.
接下這招吧
You misjudged.
失策…
There's no point in us doing this.
做這種事一點意義也沒有
What Silvia did are wrong.
希爾維雅的做法是錯的
You should know it.
你也應該明白才對
Ridiculous.
笑話…
It's no use saying anything now.
事到如今 多言無益
There's no turning back the clock.
時光不會倒流
We can't go back.
無法回到過去
My body and soul
我的身心…
have long been devoted to love.
早已為了愛奉獻一切
Isn't that the same with you?
這一點 你不也是一樣嗎
Noir.
諾瓦爾
Stop, Grauphon.
住手 格勞芬
Born for love, die for love.
為愛而生 為愛而死
W-What's wrong?
怎…怎麼了
Born for love, die for love.?
為愛而生 為愛而死…是嗎
These people are really troublesome.
這些人真讓人笑不出來
Alright, let's go.
好了 我們走吧
Rouge.
露瓊
Oh my.
真是的…
You silly man.
你這個蠢男人
So are you.
你也是啊…
Right.
是啊
Please
拜託你…
stop Silvia.
阻止希爾維雅…
Stop her.
阻止她…
Okay.
好
I promise you.
我答應你
There's another person…
又有一個人…
Maybe both of them…
說不定他們兩人都…
Before,
以前…
any time one of us nine had a fight,
九個人裡 只要有人吵架
you'd step in.
你就會介入勸架
Please
拜託你
help me.
幫幫我吧
This is to save Silvia.
這是為了拯救希爾維雅
But I…
可是我…
You said it's about survival.
你說過這是為了"活下去"吧
Aes!
臭艾斯
That low-spirited you is already dead.
那個沒志氣的你早就死了
If you die,
如果你死掉
that means I'm dead too.
那就表示我也死了
Don't just drag me down with you.
不要隨便拖人下水
The so-called survival
所謂的"活著"
is about choosing and making your own decisions.
是要自己選擇 自己做出決定
Trust yourself.
要相信自己
Trust yourself?
相信自己…
You said there might be another way, right?
你說過或許還有其他方法對吧
Do you really think so?
你真的這麼想嗎
I should be able to find
應該能找到才對
a new path,
找到新的道路
a better path.
更好的道路
You seem to care a lot about the black reactor.
您似乎很在意黑色反應爐
Not really.
也還好
Let me ask you.
欸
Are you really taking us to see Gene?
你不是要帶我們去吉恩那裡嗎
Weird. Where is this?
奇怪 這裡是哪裡啊
What?
什麼
Sorry.
不好意思
I seem to have lost my way.
看來我似乎是迷路了
You…
你果然…
Don't need to be that angry.
也用不著這麼生氣吧
Isn't life like wandering in a maze?
人生不就是 至死都有如徘徊在迷宮之中嗎
What a cliche!
真是陳腐的話語
Do you know why I say so?
知道為何被我說是陳腐嗎
Because your ideas lack depth.
因為裡面沒有內涵
Do you know why you ideas lack depth?
知道為何沒有內涵嗎
Because you have an empty mind.
因為你只是個內心空空如也的存在
Your comments are very harsh.
還真是嚴厲的評語
I brought the guests here as you told me.
虧我還遵照妳的指示 將客人帶來這裡了說
You morphed into someone's face
幻化成某人的臉
and mimicked someone's behaviors.
做出某人的舉止
But you actually crave others'…
但其實是個 一直渴求著某人而活的…
What a boring man.
無聊男子
Oh my.
哎呀…
I've always hated you.
我一直都很討厭你
Well, that's great.
那可真是太好了…
Noir.
諾瓦爾
I need your power.
我需要你的力量
Please help me.
助我一臂之力吧
Please.
拜託你
Dad.
爸爸
The improvisational performance is about to end.
即興劇即將告終
Looks like the final is coming.
看來最後的表演將要到來
Right.
沒錯
You are the star.
妳就是主角喔
Script?
劇本?
Haven't I told you?
我沒告訴過妳嗎
You don't need a script for your role.
妳所扮演的角色不需要劇本
All you have to do is get on the stage and end the show.
妳只要上台 將舞台落幕就好
That's it.
只要這樣就行了
I'm giving you one last chance.
最後再給妳一次機會
Become one of us.
成為我們的同志吧
Sacrifice your life for your kin.
為了同胞 獻出妳的生命吧
Life?
生命?
Your id is an analysis machine,
你的伊德是分析機…
a main unit of the decryptor.
解析裝置的主要元件
Once your id is installed, it cannot be removed.
一旦安裝 將無法卸下
You will proudly
妳將為了拯救涅安
sacrifice your life to save Neans.
自豪地奉獻出自己的生命
No way!
我絕對不要
And,
而且…
if I die, I'll never have Broma chocolate again.
要是死掉 就再也吃不到布洛瑪巧克力了
Eden.
伊甸
Gene Junghardt, you're here too.
吉恩・容格哈特也在
You are…
你是…
Aes?
艾斯?
He's one of us.
他是自己人
He saved me.
是他救了我
If you shoot me with that gun,
你要是用那把槍對我開火
the person who will die is definitely you.
那死的人肯定會是你
Alice.
艾莉斯
I-I'm sorry.
對…對不起
That's not the point. I saw it.
這些不是重點 我看到了
I saw that guy called Puppetmaster.
看到那個叫做"操偶師"的傢伙…
I saw the true face under his mask.
他面具底下的真面目
Let's set out.
那我們出發吧
To close the curtain on the old world,
將舊世界的舞台閉幕
and
並且…
open the curtain of the new world.
拉開新世界的帷幕
(Episode 12: Mask Graveyard)
(12 面具墳場)
Please, Rouge.
拜託妳 露瓊
Don't lose.
別輸了…
Do you know how long can Neans survive on Venus?
妳知道在金星上的涅安 有多久的壽命嗎
Three years.
三年…
They can only survive for three years.
他們只能存活三年
In an environment that even Nean with strong body
在這個連擁有強韌肉體的涅安
could not withstand,
都無法承受的殘酷環境中
countless comrades have lost their lives here.
無數同伴的生命就此逝去
This planet, Venus,
這個星球 金星
is just as much a battleground
也和過去的火星一樣
as Mars was.
是個戰場
Gene said that freeing the Neans would lead to chaos and conflicts in the world.
吉恩說過要是解放涅安 將會導致世界混亂 紛爭四起
However, that is wrong.
然而 這是錯的
The war never stops.
戰爭從來就沒停過
The war between Neans and humans
涅安與人類之間的戰爭
has never stopped since the birth of Immortal Nine.
從我們九人誕生以來就沒停過
Please win.
求求妳 一定要贏…
If you lose,
妳要是輸了
I'll have to…
我就又得將妳…
She succeeded.
成功了
You cannot possibly win me, who's fighting with free will.
以自由意志戰鬥的我 妳是絕對贏不了的
Absolutely.
絕對贏不了
You're just a puppet who only does what you're told.
妳這個只會聽命行事的傀儡
Rouge.
露瓊
No.
不對…
I've made my choice.
我做出了選擇
This is my free will.
這是我的意志
So,
那麼…
I'm sure you won't regret it.
想必妳不會後悔
After all, you chose to die.
畢竟這是妳自己選擇的死亡…
Before your functioning stops,
在機能停止之前
take a good look with your eyes
用妳的雙眼好好看著吧
and see the moment the world changes.
看看世界改變的瞬間
Damn.
可惡…
Oh no.
糟糕…
Naomi.
直美…
Help…
幫…
Help me.
幫幫我…
Naomi.
直美…
Naomi?
直美…?
Idiot Naomi.
笨蛋直美…
Do you still put orders first?
果然還是以命令為優先嗎
You are pathetic.
真是可憐
Just live as free as I do.
像我這樣自由地活著不就得了
Are you looking for the control room of the reactor?
敢問是在尋找反應爐的控制室嗎
If so, it's right ahead.
是的話 就在前面
Why do you help me?
為什麼要幫我
Help you?
幫妳?
I've said it.
我不是說過了嗎
I just want to enjoy it.
我只是想要享受罷了
Before I take my last breath and my heart stops beating,
在呼吸停止 心跳停止
even function stops, I'll enjoy to the fullest.
甚至是所有機能停止之前 盡情享受
If that girl can't make it,
要是那個姑娘失手
you just make the reactor go out of control
就讓反應爐失控
and destroy this plant to prevent the release of Code Eve.
毀掉這個設施 藉以阻止CODE EVE的解放
I think that's what you're planning.
你們應該是這麼打算的吧
Interesting.
實在有趣
Those Visitors are really resolute.
那些來訪者想法還真是時髦
And I am very much looking forward to
而妳會選擇什麼樣的未來
what kind of future you will choose, Naomi Orthmann.
我也很是期待喔 直美・奧德曼
No.
不…
Goodbye, First.
再會了 First
Access authenticated.
通過存取認證
Safety device released.
解除安全裝置
-Sorry. -Input wave changes are allowed.
-不好意思啊 -同意進行輸入波變更
-Although you've been trying to warn everyone, -Warning.
-雖然你一直盡力在警告 -警告
-I've already blocked your voice inside. -Input wave energy has exceeded specified values.
-但我已經把你的聲音封鎖起來了 -輸入波能量已超過指定數值
-Alright, I know it's dangerous. -10 percent.
-好好好 我知道危險… -10%
-20 percent.
-20%
30 percent.
30%
Warning!
警告
-There's a risk of explosion. -Input wave energy has exceeded the danger level.
-有爆炸之虞是吧 -輸入波能量已超過危險值
-What happens if it explodes?
-爆炸的話 不知道會怎麼樣呢
-Everyone will die, right? -40 percent.
-大家都會死吧 -40%
-50 percent.
-50%
-We'd all be doomed together. -60 percent.
-大家全都會一起完蛋 -60%
Everyone…
全都一起…
Warning: Input wave energy has exceeded the danger level.
警告 輸入波能量已超過危險值
70 percent.
70%
80 percent.
80%
Warning!
警告
-Rouge. -Please reduce the input wave energy below the danger level.
-露瓊 -請將輸入波能量降至危險值以下
Warning!
警告
Input wave energy has exceeded 100 percent.
輸入波能量已超過100%
Annoying!
吼唷
-I got it. -110 percent.
-我知道了啦 -110%
-Rouge. -120 percent.
-露瓊… -120%
Rouge.
露瓊…
I'm here.
我在這裡…
Huh?
咦
Idiot Naomi.
笨蛋直美…
You're still alive.
還活著…
What?
喔?
I'm sorry.
對不起
Mm.
喔…
I won't ask you where you ran to.
我不會問妳跑去哪裡
But is it okay that you came back?
但妳這樣跑回來沒關係嗎
Don't you have things to do?
妳不是有事要完成嗎
Is this your reasonable judgment?
這是妳的合理判斷嗎
I don't know.
我不知道啦…
This isn't reasonable at all.
這一點也不合理…
It can't be explained by reason.
也無法解釋
It's not something I have to risk to do.
而且也不是非得抗命去做的事
Am I broken or something?
我是不是壞掉了啊
I don't quite understand.
我也不是很懂…
But isn't that what friends are for?
但朋友不就是這樣嗎…
Friends?
朋友…
We might act like humans.
我們這樣 說不定很像是人類才會做的事呢…
Then, what are you going to do?
然後 接下來要怎麼辦呢…
I've decided
我決定了
I'm going with you.
我要跟妳一起走
Idiot, what are you doing?
笨蛋 妳在做什麼
With Eden as a precedent,
有伊甸的例子在…
it should be okay for a while.
一段時間的話 應該是沒問題的…
I need you to get this done
快去把這一切搞定…
and bring it back to me.
再拿來還我吧…
Grauphon.
格勞芬…
I always want you to be with me until the end.
我一直希望 你能陪我直到最後…
Did Gene Junghardt escape?
吉恩・容格哈特逃走了?
It seems Double-Headed Aerkos has betrayed us.
看來雙頭的亞格斯背叛了
Never mind.
已經無所謂了
We are going to make our world…
現在就要將我們的世界給…
How would you…
妳怎麼會…
Rouge.
露瓊
Did you
難不成…
give your own id…
妳將自己的伊德給…
Are you crazy?
妳是瘋了嗎
I just lent her.
我只是借她而已
You two.
妳們兩個
Ash, Aes.
亞許 艾斯
Don't worry, Rouge.
放心吧 露瓊
Gene and Eden are both fine.
吉恩還有伊甸都沒事
What kind of device is this?
這是什麼的裝置嗎
This belongs to the Usurpers.
是篡奪者的東西
I've been investigating a lot of Usurper devices on Mars.
我在火星上 調查了不少篡奪者的裝置
However,
不過…
they said I was tomb raiding.
卻被那些小姐稱作是"盜墓"就是了
This is the data for Code Eve.
這是CODE EVE的資料
But,
可是…
how…
怎麼會…
What about Cyan?
希安呢
Well…
呃…
She…
她…
My job is to gather these poor puppets
我的任務是聚集這些可憐人偶
then liberate them,
然後解放他們
and save them.
並拯救他們
Rouge.
露瓊
This guy is Junghardt.
這傢伙是容格
He is Dr. Roy Junghardt.
他就是羅伊・容格哈特博士
Are you free?
妳是自由的嗎
Rouge Redstar.
露瓊・雷德斯塔